<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" version="2.0" xml:base="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/">
  <channel>
    <title>CISA TIPS feed</title>
    <link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/</link>
    <description>US-CERT Tips describe and offer advice about common security issues for non-technical computer users.  Tips are restricted to a single topic, although complex issues may span multiple tips.  Each tip builds upon the knowledge, both terminology and content, of those published prior to it.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    
    <item>
	<title>Privacy and Mobile Device Apps</title>
	<link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/st19-003</link>
	<description>Original release date: July 9, 2019 | Last revised: November 15, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h1&gt;What are the risks associated with mobile device apps?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications (apps) on your smartphone or other mobile devices can be convenient tools to access the news, get directions, pick up a ride share, or play games. But these tools can also put your privacy at risk. When you download an app, it may ask for permission to access personal information—such as email contacts, calendar inputs, call logs, and location data—from your device. Apps may gather this information for legitimate purposes—for example, a ride-share app will need your location data in order to pick you up. However, you should be aware that app developers will have access to this information and may share it with third parties, such as companies who develop targeted ads based on your location and interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;How can you avoid malicious apps and limit the information apps collect about you?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Before installing an app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid potentially harmful apps (PHAs).&lt;/strong&gt; Reduce the risk of downloading PHAs by limiting your download sources to official app stores, such as your device’s manufacturer or operating system app store. Do not download from unknown sources or install untrusted enterprise certificates. Additionally—because malicious apps have been known to slip through the security of even reputable app stores—always read the reviews and research the developer before downloading and installing an app.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be savvy with your apps.&lt;/strong&gt; Before downloading an app, make sure you understand what information the app will access. Read the permissions the app is requesting and determine whether the data it is asking to access is related to the purpose of the app. Read the app’s privacy policy to see if, or how, your data will be shared. Consider foregoing the app if the policy is vague regarding with whom it shares your data or if the permissions request seems excessive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;On already installed apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review app permissions.&lt;/strong&gt; Review the permissions each app has. Ensure your installed apps only have access to the information they need, and remove unnecessary permissions from each app. Consider removing apps with excessive permissions. Pay special attention to apps that have access to your contact list, camera, storage, location, and microphone.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit location permissions.&lt;/strong&gt; Some apps have access to the mobile device’s location services and thus have access to the user’s approximate physical location. For apps that require access to location data to function, consider limiting this access to when the app is in use only.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep app software up to date.&lt;/strong&gt; Apps with out-of-date software may be at risk of exploitation of known vulnerabilities. Protect your mobile device from malware by installing app updates as they are released.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delete apps you do not need.&lt;/strong&gt; To avoid unnecessary data collection, uninstall apps you no longer use.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be cautious with signing into apps with social network accounts.&lt;/strong&gt; Some apps are integrated with social network sites—in these cases, the app can collect information from your social network account and vice versa. Ensure you are comfortable with this type of information sharing before you sign into an app via your social network account. Alternatively, use your email address and a unique password to sign in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What additional steps can you take to secure data on your mobile devices?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limit activities on public Wi-Fi networks.&lt;/strong&gt; Public Wi-Fi networks at places such as airports and coffee shops present an opportunity for attackers to intercept sensitive information. When using a public or unsecured wireless connection, avoid using apps and websites that require personal information, e.g., a username and password. Additionally, turn off the Bluetooth setting on your devices when not in use. (See &lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-017"&gt;Cybersecurity for Electronic Devices&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be cautious when charging.&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid connecting your smartphone to any computer or charging station that you do not control, such as a charging station at an airport terminal or a shared computer at a library. Connecting a mobile device to a computer using a USB cable can allow software running on that computer to interact with the phone in ways you may not anticipate. For example, a malicious computer could gain access to your sensitive data or install new software. (See &lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST11-001"&gt;Holiday Traveling with Personal Internet-Enabled Devices&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect your device from theft.&lt;/strong&gt; Having physical access to a device makes it easier for an attacker to extract or corrupt information. Do not leave your device unattended in public or in easily accessible areas.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protect your data if your device is stolen.&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure your device requires a password or biometric identifier to access it, so if is stolen, thieves will have limited access to its data. (See &lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords&lt;/a&gt;.) If your device is stolen, immediately contact your service provider to protect your data. (See the &lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/protect-your-mobile-device"&gt;Federal Communications Commission’s Consumer Guide: Protect Your Smart Device&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                    &lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
		        &lt;ul&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-017"&gt;Cybersecurity for Electronic Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST11-001"&gt;Holiday Traveling with Personal Internet-Enabled Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/protect-your-mobile-device"&gt;Federal Communications Commission’s Consumer Guide: Protect Your Smart Device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        &lt;/ul&gt;Author: CISA
            &lt;div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p class="privacy-and-terms"&gt;This product is provided subject to this &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/privacy/notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Use&lt;/a&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 12:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>CISA</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">12511 at https://us-cert.cisa.gov</guid>
    </item>
<item>
	<title>Best Practices for Securing Election Systems</title>
	<link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST19-002</link>
	<description>Original release date: May 21, 2019 | Last revised: November 2, 2020&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;By adhering to cybersecurity best practices, election organizations—including state, local, tribal, and territorial (SLTT) governments—can improve the security of their election systems. The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) developed the best practices in this tip from lessons learned through engagements with SLTT governments, election stakeholders, and others. Organizations can implement these best practices, which harden enterprise networks and strengthen election infrastructure, at little or no cost. CISA’s election systems best practices cover the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="accordion-enclosure"&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software and Patch Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing an enterprise-wide software and patch management program reduces the likelihood of an organization experiencing significant cybersecurity incidents. A software and patch management program includes the establishment of an enterprise-wide inventory list, which provides an organization with greater insight into the software running on its networks and associated vulnerabilities. The organization can then use the inventory list to help identify and mitigate the risks to its election-related information technology (IT) infrastructure. Mitigations often include implementing application whitelisting, a best practice. (See &lt;a href="https://www.cyber.gov.au/publications/implementing-application-whitelisting"&gt;Implementing Application Whitelisting&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CISA has observed a correlation between the absence of a patch management program and the partial or complete compromise of an enterprise network due to the presence of commodity malware. Commodity malware is widely available, has minimal or no customization, and is used by a wide range of threat actors. A partial or complete compromise could lead to additional impacts, including ransomware infection and the theft of sensitive data, which may include personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure to deploy patches in a timely manner can make an organization a target of opportunity, even for less sophisticated actors, increasing the risk of compromise. If an enterprise-wide patch management solution is too costly, an organization should consider enabling automatic updates. CISA recommends organizations subscribe to the &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas"&gt;National Cybersecurity Awareness System&lt;/a&gt; for alerts about security updates, threats, and vulnerabilities. This will assist organizations in maintaining situational awareness of critical vulnerabilities present in software widely used throughout their enterprise environments. It is vital to act quickly to apply patches, especially if there is an associated vulnerability being exploited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retaining and adequately securing logs from both network devices and local hosts supports triage and remediation of cybersecurity events. An organization can analyze the logs to determine the impact of cybersecurity events and ascertain whether an incident has occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Centralized Log Management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations should set up centralized log management:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Forward logs from local hosts to a centralized log management server—often referred to as a security information and event management (SIEM) tool. CISA has observed threat actors attempting to delete local logs to remove on-site evidence of their activities. By sending logs to a SIEM tool, an organization can reduce the likelihood of malicious log deletion.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Correlate logs from both network and host security devices. By reviewing logs from multiple sources, an organization can better triage an individual event and determine its impact to the organization as a whole.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Review both centralized and local log management policies to maximize efficiency and retain historical data. CISA recommends that organizations retain critical logs for a minimum of one year, if possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Update PowerShell and Enable Advanced Logging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to setting up centralized logging, organizations should ensure that instances of PowerShell are logging activity. PowerShell is a cross-platform command-line shell and scripting language that is a component of Microsoft Windows. CISA has observed threat actors, including advanced persistent threat (APT) actors, using PowerShell to hide their malicious activities. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Update PowerShell instances to version 5.0 or later and uninstall all earlier PowerShell versions. Logs from PowerShell prior to version 5.0 are either non-existent or do not record enough detail to aid in enterprise monitoring and incident response activities.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ensure PowerShell 5.0 instances have module, script block, and transcription logging enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network Segmentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations can limit the impact of a cybersecurity incident by enforcing network segmentation. Proper network segmentation is an effective security mechanism to prevent an intruder from propagating exploits or laterally moving around an internal network. On a poorly segmented network, intruders are able to extend their impact to control critical devices or gain access to sensitive data and intellectual property. Segregation separates network segments based on role and functionality. A securely segregated network can contain malicious occurrences, reducing the impact from intruders in the event they gain a foothold somewhere inside the network. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-001"&gt;Securing Network Infrastructure Devices&lt;/a&gt;.) During on-site engagements, CISA has observed organizations without effective network segmentation suffer commodity malware compromises of all Windows hosts in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations should define their distinct organizational components (e.g., human resources, IT administration, demilitarized zone, elections) and create a separate Virtual Local Area Network (VLAN) for each component. Alternatively, if feasible, organizations should implement physical network segmentation for each component. CISA recommends that organizations restrict traffic between VLANs following the principle of least privilege. See below for additional guidance for protecting elections-specific VLANs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Segment Elections-Related Hosts from the General User Network&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use dedicated servers and workstations for elections-related tasks. Organizations should never allow workstations with elections-related roles—such as submitting election results to a reporting server—to be used for general purpose computing, such as browsing the internet. Organizations should ensure up-to-date patching of workstations and servers dedicated to elections-related tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Follow the principle of least privilege. Organizations should only allow elections-related VLANs to communicate with machines unrelated to elections on an as-needed basis. Other network traffic should be explicitly denied (e.g., by using a &lt;code&gt;DENY/DENY&lt;/code&gt; ruleset).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Apply the appropriate technical controls (e.g., implement Group Policy Object [GPO] and firewall rules) to restrict general internet browsing from elections-related workstations and servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block Suspicious Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many organizations set their security devices to alert on suspicious activity instead of blocking it. When an organization does not block suspicious activity by default, it increases the likelihood of adverse events that allow an adversary to compromise IT resources. Organizations should follow best practices in disabling network protocols known to spread malware, such as Server Message Block version 1 (SMB v1). (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/current-activity/2017/01/16/SMB-Security-Best-Practices"&gt;SMB Security Best Practices&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Prevent Malware and Malicious Traffic&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations should perform the following actions to block malicious traffic and malware:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enable security features. Many network appliances, cloud services, and security software (e.g., host intrusion prevention systems) have features—not enabled by default—that block malicious traffic. CISA recommends that organizations enable these features. Note: organizations should thoroughly test changes before implementing them in production environments.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Scan all incoming emails for malicious attachments and links prior to delivery, and quarantine emails, as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Train employees to recognize phishing attempts and ensure a process exists for reporting and triaging phishing emails.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Block macros from running in documents throughout enterprise. (See &lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/cert/2016/06/who-needs-to-exploit-vulnerabilities-when-you-have-macros.html"&gt;Who Needs to Exploit Vulnerabilities When You Have Macros?&lt;/a&gt; for more information.)
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Before restricting macro-enabled documents, determine if any users need macro-enabled documents to perform their work functions. If macros are not used, disable them by GPO.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;If blocking macro-enabled documents across an organization is too restrictive, consider alternative solutions, such as only allowing macro-enabled documents for specific users or blocking macros from running when received as email attachments from external users.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Disable SMB v1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of recent engagements, CISA has observed threat actors using SMB v1 to spread malware across organizations. Based on this specific threat, CISA recommends organizations consider the following actions to protect their networks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Disable SMB v1 internally on their network.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Block all versions of SMB at the network boundary by blocking Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) port 445 with related protocols on User Datagram Protocol ports 137–138 and TCP port 139.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credential Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing passwords and using strong passwords are important steps in preventing unauthorized access to databases, applications, and other election infrastructure assets. Multi-factor authentication (MFA), in particular, can help prevent adversaries from gaining access to an organization’s assets even if passwords are compromised through phishing attacks or other means. Threat actors have the capability to defeat single-factor authentication, especially when passwords are weak (e.g., common or trivial passwords) or—taking into account credential reuse—have been exposed in unrelated third-party breaches. CISA has published the following guidance to assist organizations with preventing unauthorized access:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Implement MFA to prevent unauthorized access, particularly by external users (including APT actors). (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/alerts/TA18-276A"&gt;Using Rigorous Credential Control to Mitigate Trusted Network Exploitation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012"&gt;Supplementing Passwords&lt;/a&gt;.) MFA requires users to present two or more credentials (e.g., a password and the use of a hardware token) at login to verify their identity before being granted access to a given system. Organizations should consider implementing MFA for voter registration, election night reporting, and associated enterprise IT systems.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enforce password best practices, including the use of unique and complex passwords to access different systems and accounts. Accounts with additional privileges (e.g., administrator accounts) should have password requirements that are more stringent than those for standard users. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If possible, use a local administration password solution. (See &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/previous-versions/mt227395(v=msdn.10)"&gt;Local Administrator Password Solution&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish a Baseline for Host and Network Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An organization’s IT personnel are critical in determining what is and is not normal and expected host or network activity. With the appropriate tools, IT personnel are well positioned to determine whether observed anomalous activity warrants further investigation. During on-site engagements, CISA uses the following metrics to establish a baseline for expected network- and host-based activity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Network Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Specific metrics should include expected bandwidth usage for
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The organization,&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Each user (if possible),&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Remote access,&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Ports,&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Protocols, and&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;File types.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Organizations should consider variables such as the time of day traffic occurs, i.e., remote access is more suspicious occurring at 1 a.m. than during standard business hours.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Including additional metrics—such as the destination of network traffic and the destination Internet Protocol (IP) address’s geographic location—establishes a more detailed baseline.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Once a baseline is established, an organization should review the results to determine if they align with industry best practices. (See &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/elections-resources-best-practices/"&gt;Handbook for Elections Infrastructure Security&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Organizations should compare their baseline traffic with the rules from their boundary firewalls to ensure that the rules are acting as intended and align with industry best practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Host Baseline&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Organizations can establish a baseline by creating a “gold image” for workstations and servers. A gold image contains an organization’s standard set of necessary, trusted applications installed for the set of systems for which it is designed. Once created, the organization should document the gold image’s configuration. Organizations should also document approved variations from the gold image, such as tools used by the organization’s network or security teams. Examples of configuration information that may be useful in identifying anomalous activity include
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Hashes of critical operating system files;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Software used for remote host access (e.g., a Virtual Private Network client);&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;An organization-wide approved software list, which can help determine if detected software is not approved for the organization; and&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Information on configurations and settings that can be used to automatically launch software after a reboot, including services, scheduled tasks, and autorun programs. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In addition to reviewing files on a system, organizations should review the location of file installation and the validity of the files’ digital certificate, if possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization-Wide IT Guidance and Policies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing and maintaining guidance and policies targeted to specific situations and that assist in implementing best practices throughout the organization benefits an organization’s IT ecosystem. Guidance and policies that can significantly benefit an organization’s cyber hygiene include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A cybersecurity incident response plan and corresponding communications plan (see &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Incident Handling Elections Final 508.pdf"&gt;Incident Handling Overview for Election Officials&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/elections-resources-best-practices/"&gt;Handbook for Elections Infrastructure Security&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.belfercenter.org/publication/election-cyber-incident-communications-plan-template"&gt;Election Cyber Incident Communications Plan Template&lt;/a&gt;);

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;At a minimum, include
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Roles and responsibilities of the parties in regard to the plans;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;24/7 contact information for the parties with critical roles;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Incident severity thresholds and associated role-based actions taken at those thresholds;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;A policy establishing a user’s responsibility to notify IT personnel of an IT security event; and&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Guidance that helps determine when the organization should notify external parties, such as CISA, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the Election Infrastructure Information Sharing and Analysis Center (EI-ISAC) (see Election Infrastructure Subsector Communications Protocol, EI-ISAC Formalized Notification Process, both available from CISA upon request, and &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/publication/cyber-incident-reporting-unified-message-reporting-federal-government"&gt;Cyber Incident Reporting Unified Message&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Patch management policies;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Password management policies; and&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An approved software list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guidance and policies like these help formalize expectations for users and IT personnel. Organizations should formally document any exceptions to official guidance and policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;CISA On-Site Engagement Preparation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CISA provides expert intrusion analysis and mitigation guidance to clients who lack in-house capability or require additional assistance with responding to a cyber incident. CISA supports federal departments and agencies, state and local governments, the private sector (industry and critical infrastructure asset owners and operators), academia, and international organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before CISA can approve an organization’s Request for Technical Assistance (RTA) to provide on-network assistance to SLTT government agencies as part of a hunt or incident response, CISA requires proof that the organization has implemented login consent banners that appear on the screens of all servers and workstations accessed by the organization’s staff and within the scope of the assistance. This login consent banner cannot conflict with other IT resource policies, procedures, or trainings. In many situations, CISA has successfully helped government organizations update their banners in a way that allows CISA assistance. CISA cannot approve deployment to an on-site SLTT engagement involving on-network assistance unless the RTA and login consent banners are approved. For more information regarding consent banners, see the &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Elections%20Infrastructure%20Questionnaire.pdf"&gt;Election Infrastructure Questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CISA also strongly recommends that organizations maintain current internal documentation related to the &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Elections%20Infrastructure%20Questionnaire.pdf"&gt;Election Infrastructure Questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;. CISA developed the questionnaire to assist organizational documentation of election infrastructure cybersecurity posture and to identify key interdependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice and Consent Banners for Computer Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section identifies recommended elements in computing system notice and consent banners and provides an example banner. This section does not include legal advice, and the information it contains is not guaranteed to be accurate or complete. Anyone reviewing or developing a notice and consent banner should consider consulting an attorney and should note that laws can change rapidly, differ from jurisdiction to jurisdiction, and can be subject to various interpretations by various entities. Further, notice and consent banners can require tailoring based on the specific circumstances and legal jurisdiction at issue. The elements or the examples may be inadvisable depending on the entity or situation. Applicable laws may include the Fourth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, any similar provisions in state constitutions, and relevant federal- and state-level statutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Notice and Consent Banner Elements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner expressly covers monitoring of data and communications in transit rather than just accessing data at rest.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “You consent to the unrestricted monitoring, interception, recording, and searching of all communications and data transiting, traveling to or from, or stored on this system.”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner provides that information in transit or stored on the system may be disclosed to any entity, including to government entities.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “You consent, without restriction, to all communications and data transiting, traveling to or from, or stored on this system being disclosed to any entity, including to government entities.”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner states that monitoring will be for any purpose.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “…at any time and for any purpose.”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner states that monitoring may be done by the entity or any person or entity authorized by the entity.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “…monitoring or disclosure to any entity authorized by [ENTITY].”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner explains to users that they have “no reasonable expectation of privacy” regarding communications or data in transit or stored on the system.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “You are acknowledging that you have no reasonable expectation of privacy regarding your use of this system.”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner clarifies that the given consent covers personal use of the system (such as personal emails or websites, or use on breaks or after hours) as well as official or work-related use.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “…including work-related use and personal use without exception….”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner is definitive about the fact of monitoring, rather than being conditional or speculative.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “…will be monitored…”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The banner expressly obtains consent from the user and does not merely provide notification.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Note: click-through banners can be best because they force the user to interact with the language.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Note: supporting processes should generally also preserve/provide evidence of the user’s agreement to the terms.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “By using this system, you are acknowledging and consenting to…”&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Example: “By clicking [ACCEPT] below…you consent to…”&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Nothing in the remainder of the banner or associated policies, agreements, training, etc., is inconsistent with, or otherwise undercuts, the elements of the banner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Example Banner&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By clicking [ACCEPT] below you acknowledge and consent to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All communications and data transiting, traveling to or from, or stored on this system will be monitored. You consent to the unrestricted monitoring, interception, recording, and searching of all communications and data transiting, traveling to or from, or stored on this system at any time and for any purpose by [the ENTITY] and by any person or entity, including government entities, authorized by [the ENTITY]. You also consent to the unrestricted disclosure of all communications and data transiting, traveling to or from, or stored on this system at any time and for any purpose to any person or entity, including government entities, authorized by [the ENTITY]. You are acknowledging that you have no reasonable expectation of privacy regarding your use of this system. These acknowledgments and consents cover all use of the system, including work-related use and personal use without exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class="accordion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Elections-Specific Guidance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CISA Election Security Information:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/cisa/election-security"&gt;https://www.dhs.gov/cisa/election-security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incident Handling for Elections:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Incident%20Handling%20Elections%20Final%20508.pdf"&gt;https://www.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Incident%20Handling%20Elections%20Final%20508.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Election Cyber Incident Communications Plan Template for State and Local Officials:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.belfercenter.org/publication/election-cyber-incident-communications-plan-template"&gt;https://www.belfercenter.org/publication/election-cyber-incident-communications-plan-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Election Infrastructure Questionnaire:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Elections%20Infrastructure%20Questionnaire.pdf"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Elections%20Infrastructure%20Questionnaire.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing Voter Registration Data:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST16-001"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST16-001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Center for Internet Security (CIS) Handbook for Elections Infrastructure Security:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/elections-resources-best-practices/"&gt;https://www.cisecurity.org/elections-resources-best-practices/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Patch Management Best Practices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding Patches and Software Updates:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-006"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Special Publication (SP) 800-40 Rev. 3: Guide to Enterprise Patch Management Technologies:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-40/rev-3/final"&gt;https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-40/rev-3/final&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CIS Top 20 Security Controls:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/controls/"&gt;https://www.cisecurity.org/controls/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Ransomware Best Practices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protecting Against Ransomware:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST19-001"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST19-001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Password Best Practices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementing Passwords:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIST SP 800-63B Digital Identity Guidelines Authentication and Lifecycle Management:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-3/sp800-63b.html"&gt;https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-3/sp800-63b.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Enterprise Best Practices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing Enterprise Wireless Networks:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-247"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-247&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website Security:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-006"&gt;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: due to variances among enterprise networks and associated election infrastructure, organizations should not consider these best practices a prescriptive solution for all cybersecurity risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
		        &lt;ul&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.us-cert.gov/sites/default/files/publications/Elections%20Infrastructure%20Questionnaire.pdf"&gt;Election Infrastructure Questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        &lt;/ul&gt;Author: CISA
            &lt;div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p class="privacy-and-terms"&gt;This product is provided subject to this &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/privacy/notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Use&lt;/a&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>CISA</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">12372 at https://us-cert.cisa.gov</guid>
    </item>
<item>
	<title>Protecting Against Ransomware</title>
	<link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST19-001</link>
	<description>Original release date: April 11, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is ransomware?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is a type of malware threat actors use to infect computers and encrypt computer files until a ransom is paid. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-271"&gt;Protecting Against Malicious Code&lt;/a&gt; for more information on malware.) After the initial infection, ransomware will attempt to spread to connected systems, including shared storage drives and other accessible computers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the threat actor&amp;rsquo;s ransom demands are not met (i.e., if the victim does not pay the ransom), the files or encrypted data will usually remain encrypted and unavailable to the victim. Even after a ransom has been paid to unlock encrypted files, threat actors will sometimes demand additional payments, delete a victim&amp;rsquo;s data, refuse to decrypt the data, or decline to provide a working decryption key to restore the victim&amp;rsquo;s access. The Federal Government does not support paying ransomware demands. (See the FBI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/incidents-of-ransomware-on-the-rise/incidents-of-ransomware-on-the-rise"&gt;ransomware article&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How does ransomware work?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware identifies the drives on an infected system and begins to encrypt the files within each drive. Ransomware generally adds an extension to the encrypted files, such as &lt;code&gt;.aaa&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.micro&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.encrypted&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.ttt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.xyz&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.zzz&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.locky&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.crypt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.cryptolocker&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.vault&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;.petya&lt;/code&gt;, to show that the files have been encrypted&amp;mdash;the file extension used is unique to the ransomware type.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the ransomware has completed file encryption, it creates and displays a file or files containing instructions on how the victim can pay the ransom. If the victim pays the ransom, the threat actor may provide a cryptographic key that the victim can use to unlock the files, making them accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How is ransomware delivered?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is commonly delivered through phishing emails or via &amp;ldquo;drive-by downloads.&amp;rdquo; Phishing emails often appear as though they have been sent from a legitimate organization or someone known to the victim and entice the user to click on a malicious link or open a malicious attachment. A &amp;ldquo;drive-by download&amp;rdquo; is a program that is automatically downloaded from the internet without the user&amp;rsquo;s consent or often without their knowledge. It is possible the malicious code may run after download, without user interaction. After the malicious code has been run, the computer becomes infected with ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What can I do to protect my data and networks?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back up your computer.&lt;/strong&gt; Perform frequent backups of your system and other important files, and verify your backups regularly. If your computer becomes infected with ransomware, you can restore your system to its previous state using your backups. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Store your backups separately.&lt;/strong&gt; Best practice is to store your backups on a separate device that cannot be accessed from a network, such as on an external hard drive. Once the backup is completed, make sure to disconnect the external hard drive, or separate device from the network or computer. (See the Software Engineering Institute&amp;rsquo;s page on &lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/sei_blog/2017/05/ransomware-best-practices-for-prevention-and-response.html"&gt;Ransomware&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Train your organization.&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations should ensure that they provide cybersecurity awareness training to their personnel. Ideally, organizations will have regular, mandatory cybersecurity awareness training sessions to ensure their personnel are informed about current cybersecurity threats and threat actor techniques. To improve workforce awareness, organizations can test their personnel with phishing assessments that simulate real-world phishing emails.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What can I do to prevent ransomware infections?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update and patch your computer.&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure your applications and operating systems (OSs) have been updated with the latest patches. Vulnerable applications and OSs are the target of most ransomware attacks. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-006"&gt;Understanding Patches and Software Updates&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use caution with links and when entering website addresses. &lt;/strong&gt;Be careful when clicking directly on links in emails, even if the sender appears to be someone you know. Attempt to independently verify website addresses (e.g., contact your organization&amp;#39;s helpdesk, search the internet for the sender organization&amp;rsquo;s website or the topic mentioned in the email). Pay attention to the website addresses you click on, as well as those you enter yourself. Malicious website addresses often appear almost identical to legitimate sites, often using a slight variation in spelling or a different domain (e.g., &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;.net&lt;/code&gt;). (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-010"&gt;Using Caution with Email Attachments&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open email attachments with caution.&lt;/strong&gt; Be wary of opening email attachments, even from senders you think you know, particularly when attachments are compressed files or ZIP files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep your personal information safe.&lt;/strong&gt; Check a website&amp;rsquo;s security to ensure the information you submit is encrypted before you provide it. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-013"&gt;Protecting Your Privacy&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verify email senders.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are unsure whether or not an email is legitimate, try to verify the email&amp;rsquo;s legitimacy by contacting the sender directly. Do not click on any links in the email. If possible, use a previous (legitimate) email to ensure the contact information you have for the sender is authentic before you contact them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inform yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep yourself informed about recent cybersecurity threats and up to date on ransomware techniques. You can find information about known phishing attacks on the &lt;a href="https://www.antiphishing.org/"&gt;Anti-Phishing Working Group website&lt;/a&gt;. You may also want to sign up for &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/mailing-lists-and-feeds"&gt;CISA product notifications&lt;/a&gt;, which will alert you when a new Alert, Analysis Report, Bulletin, Current Activity, or Tip has been published.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use and maintain preventative software programs.&lt;/strong&gt; Install antivirus software, firewalls, and email filters&amp;mdash;and keep them updated&amp;mdash;to reduce malicious network traffic. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-004"&gt;Understanding Firewalls for Home and Small Office Use&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How do I respond to a ransomware infection?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolate the infected system.&lt;/strong&gt; Remove the infected system from all networks, and disable the computer&amp;rsquo;s wireless, Bluetooth, and any other potential networking capabilities. Ensure all shared and networked drives are disconnected whether wired or wireless. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn off other computers and devices.&lt;/strong&gt; Power-off and segregate (i.e., remove from the network) the infected computer(s). Power-off and segregate any other computers or devices that shared a network with the infected computer(s) that have not been fully encrypted by ransomware. If possible, collect and secure all infected and potentially infected computers and devices in a central location, making sure to clearly label any computers that have been encrypted. Powering-off and segregating infected computers and computers that have not been fully encrypted may allow for the recovery of partially encrypted files by specialists. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST15-003"&gt;Before You Connect a New Computer to the Internet&lt;/a&gt; for tips on how to make a computer more secure before you reconnect it to a network.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure your backups.&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure that your backup data is offline and secure. If possible, scan your backup data with an antivirus program to check that it is free of malware.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What do I do if my computer is infected with ransomware?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home users:&lt;/strong&gt; immediately contact your &lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/contact-us/field-offices"&gt;local FBI office&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.secretservice.gov/contact/field-offices/"&gt;local U.S. Secret Service office&lt;/a&gt; to request assistance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organizations:&lt;/strong&gt; immediately report ransomware incidents to your IT helpdesk or security office.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All users:&lt;/strong&gt; change all system passwords once the ransomware has been removed. You can submit ransomware files to CISA for analysis via &lt;a href="https://www.malware.us-cert.gov/MalwareSubmission/pages/submission.jsf"&gt;https://www.malware.us-cert.gov/MalwareSubmission/pages/submission.jsf&lt;/a&gt;. (See &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting and Passwords&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012"&gt;Supplementing Passwords&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;                    &lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
		        &lt;ul&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.us-cert.gov/Ransomware"&gt;CISA Ransomware page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.malware.us-cert.gov/MalwareSubmission/pages/submission.jsf"&gt;CISA Malware Analysis Submission page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/mailing-lists-and-feeds"&gt;CISA Mailing Lists and Feeds page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-271"&gt;Protecting Against Malicious Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-013"&gt;Protecting Your Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-004"&gt;Understanding Firewalls for Home and Small Office Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-006"&gt;Understanding Patches and Software Updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-010"&gt;Using Caution with Email Attachments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST13-003"&gt;Handling Destructive Malware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012"&gt;Supplementing Passwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.antiphishing.org"&gt;Anti-Phishing Working Group’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://insights.sei.cmu.edu/sei_blog/2017/05/ransomware-best-practices-for-prevention-and-response.html"&gt;Carnegie Mellon Software Engineering Institute blog post: Ransomware: Best Practices for Prevention and Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/stories/incidents-of-ransomware-on-the-rise/incidents-of-ransomware-on-the-rise"&gt;FBI article: Incidents of Ransomware on the Rise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/contact-us/field-offices/portland/news/press-releases/fbi-tech-tuesday-building-a-digital-defense-against-ransomware-at-home"&gt;FBI Tech Tuesday: Building a Digital Defense Against Ransomware at Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;		        &lt;/ul&gt;Author: CISA
            &lt;div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p class="privacy-and-terms"&gt;This product is provided subject to this &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/privacy/notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Use&lt;/a&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 16:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>CISA</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">12276 at https://us-cert.cisa.gov</guid>
    </item>
<item>
	<title>Questions Every CEO Should Ask About Cyber Risks</title>
	<link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-007</link>
	<description>Original release date: December 4, 2018 | Last revised: November 15, 2019&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;As technology continues to evolve, cyber threats continue to grow in sophistication and complexity. Cyber threats affect businesses of all sizes and require the attention and involvement of chief executive officers (CEOs) and other senior leaders. To help companies understand their risks and prepare for cyber threats, CEOs should discuss key cybersecurity risk management topics with their leadership and implement cybersecurity best practices. The best practices listed in this document have been compiled from lessons learned from incident response activities and managing cyber risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What should CEOs know about the cybersecurity threats their companies face?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEOs should ask the following questions about potential cybersecurity threats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How could cybersecurity threats affect the different functions of my business, including areas such as supply chain, public relations, finance, and human resources?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What type of critical information could be lost (e.g., trade secrets, customer data, research, personally identifiable information)?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How can my business create long-term resiliency to minimize our cybersecurity risks?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What kind of cyber threat information sharing does my business participate in? With whom does my business exchange this information?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What type of information sharing practices could my business adopt that would help foster community among the different cybersecurity groups where my business is a member?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What can CEOs do to mitigate cybersecurity threats?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following questions will help CEOs guide discussions about their cybersecurity risk with management:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the threshold for notifying executive leadership about cybersecurity threats?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the current level of cybersecurity risk for our company?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is the possible business impact to our company from our current level of cybersecurity risk?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What is our plan to address identified risks?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What cybersecurity training is available for our workforce?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What measures do we employ to mitigate insider threats?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How does our cybersecurity program apply industry standards and best practices?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Are our cybersecurity program metrics measureable and meaningful?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How comprehensive are our cybersecurity incident response plan and our business continuity and disaster recovery plan?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How often do we exercise our plans?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do our plans incorporate the whole company or are they limited to&amp;nbsp;information technology (IT)?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How prepared is my business to work with federal, state, and local government cyber incident responders and investigators, as well as contract responders and the vendor community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recommended Organizational Cybersecurity Best Practices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity best practices listed below can help organizations manage cybersecurity risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevate cybersecurity risk management discussions to the company CEO and the leadership team.&lt;/strong&gt;

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;CEO and senior company leadership engagement in defining an organization's risk strategy and levels of acceptable risk is critical to a comprehensive cybersecurity risk plan. The company CEO—with assistance from the chief information security officer, chief information officer, and the entire leadership team—should ensure that they know how their divisions affect the company’s overall cyber risk. In addition, regular discussion with the company board of directors regarding these risk decisions ensures visibility to all company decision makers.
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Executives should construct policy from the top down to ensure everyone is empowered to perform the tasks related to their role in reducing cybersecurity risk. A top-down policy defines roles and limits the power struggles that can hurt IT security.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement industry standards and best practices rather than relying solely on compliance standards or certifications.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Lower cybersecurity risks by implementing industry benchmarks and best practices (e.g., follow best practices from organizations like the &lt;a href="https://www.cisecurity.org/cybersecurity-best-practices/"&gt;Center for Internet Security&lt;/a&gt;). Organizations should tailor best practices to ensure they are relevant for their specific use cases.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Follow consistent best practices to establish an organizational baseline of expected enterprise network behavior. This allows organizations to be proactive in combatting cybersecurity threats, rather than expending resources to "put out fires."&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Compliance standards and regulations (e.g., the Federal Information Security Modernization Act) provide guidance on minimal requirements; however, there is more businesses can do to go beyond the requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluate and manage organization-specific cybersecurity risks.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Identify your organization’s critical assets and the associated impacts from cybersecurity threats to those assets to understand your organization’s specific risk exposure—whether financial, competitive, reputational, or regulatory. Risk assessment results are a key input to identify and prioritize specific protective measures, allocate resources, inform long-term investments, and develop policies and strategies to manage cybersecurity risks.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Ask the questions that are necessary to understand your security planning, operations, and security-related goals. For example, it is better to focus on the goals your organization will achieve by implementing overall security controls instead of inquiring about specific security controls, safeguards, and countermeasures.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Focus cyber enterprise risk discussions on "what-if" situations and resist the "it can't happen here" patterns of thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Create a repeatable process to cross-train employees to conduct risk and incident management as an institutional practice. Often, there are only a few employees with subject matter expertise in key areas.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensure cybersecurity risk metrics are meaningful and measurable.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;An example of a useful metric is the time it takes an organization to patch a critical vulnerability across the enterprise. In this example, reducing the days it takes to patch a vulnerability directly reduces the risk to the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;An example of a less useful metric is the number of alerts a Security Operations Center (SOC) receives in a week. There are too many variables in the number of alerts an SOC receives for this number to be consistently relevant.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop and exercise cybersecurity plans and procedures for incident response, business continuity, and disaster recovery.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;It is critical that organizations test their incident response plans across the whole organization, not just in the IT environment. Each part of the organization should know how to respond to both basic and large-scale cybersecurity incidents. Testing incident response plans and procedures can help prevent an incident from escalating.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Incident response plans should provide instructions on when to elevate an incident to the next level of leadership. Regularly exercising incident response plans enables an organization to respond to incidents quickly and minimize impacts.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retain a quality workforce.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Cybersecurity tools are only as good as the people reviewing the tools’ results. It is also important to have people who can identify the proper tools for your organization. It can take a significant amount of time to learn a complex organization’s enterprise network, making retaining skilled personnel just as important as acquiring them. There is no perfect answer to stopping all cybersecurity threats, but knowledgeable IT personnel are critical to reducing cybersecurity risks.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;New cybersecurity threats are constantly appearing. The personnel entrusted with detecting cybersecurity threats need continual training. Training increases the likelihood of personnel detecting cybersecurity threats and responding to threats in a manner consistent with industry best practices.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Ensure there is appropriate planning to account for the additional workload related to mitigating cybersecurity risks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Cybersecurity is emerging as a formal discipline with task orientation that requires specific alignments to key knowledge, skills, and abilities. The &lt;a href="http://niccs.us-cert.gov/"&gt;National Initiative for Cybersecurity Careers and Studies (NICCS)&lt;/a&gt; is a useful resource for workforce planning.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain situational awareness of cybersecurity threats.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Subscribe to notifications on emerging cybersecurity threats (e.g., &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas"&gt;National Cyber Awareness System products&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cve.mitre.org/"&gt;MITRE Common Vulnerability Exposures&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.kb.cert.org/vuls/"&gt;CERT Coordination Center Vulnerability Notes&lt;/a&gt;). If possible, create a summary on the cybersecurity threats your organization has recently faced (e.g., phishing emails, malware, ransomware) for dissemination to personnel outside of your IT department to help reinforce their role in reducing cybersecurity risk.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Explore available communities of interest. These may include sector-specific Information Sharing and Analysis Centers, the &lt;a href="https://hsin.dhs.gov/"&gt;Homeland Information Sharing Network&lt;/a&gt;, or other government and intelligence programs.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refer to the &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/cyber-essentials"&gt;Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) Cyber Essentials&lt;/a&gt; page for recommendations on managing cybersecurity risks for small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
Author: CISA
            &lt;div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p class="privacy-and-terms"&gt;This product is provided subject to this &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/privacy/notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Use&lt;/a&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>CISA</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">10543 at https://us-cert.cisa.gov</guid>
    </item>
<item>
	<title>Website Security</title>
	<link>https://us-cert.cisa.gov/ncas/tips/ST18-006</link>
	<description>Original release date: November 1, 2018 | Last revised: June 30, 2020&lt;br/&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What is website security?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website security refers to the protection of personal and organizational public-facing websites from cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why should I care about website security?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks against public-facing websites—regardless of size—are common and may result in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Website defacement,&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Loss of website availability or denial-of-service (DoS) condition,&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Compromise of sensitive customer or organizational data,&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An attacker taking control of the affected website, or&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use of website as a staging point for watering hole attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These threats affect all aspects of information security—confidentiality, integrity, and availability—and can gravely damage the reputation of the website and its owner. For example, organization and personal websites that fall victim to defacement, DoS, or data breach may experience financial loss due to eroded user trust or a decrease in website visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What steps can my organization take to protect against website attacks?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple steps organizations and security professionals should take to properly secure their websites. &lt;strong&gt;Note: &lt;/strong&gt;organizations should talk to their website hosting provider or managed service provider to discuss roles and responsibilities for implementing security measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Secure domain ecosystems.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Review registrar and Domain Name System (DNS) records for all domains.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change all default password that were provided from your domain registrar and DNS.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Default credentials are not secure—they are usually readily available on the internet. Changing default usernames and passwords will prevent an attack that leverages default credentials. (See &lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-002"&gt;Choosing and Protecting Passwords&lt;/a&gt; for information on creating strong passwords.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enforce multi-factor authentication (MFA). (See &lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-012"&gt;Supplementing Passwords&lt;/a&gt; for more information)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Monitor certificate transparency logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/ed/19-01/"&gt;CISA Emergency Directive 19-01&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/insights"&gt;CISA Cyber Insights: Mitigate DNS Infrastructure Tampering&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Secure user accounts.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enforce MFA on all internet-accessible accounts—prioritizing those with privileged access.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Implement the principle of least privilege and disable unnecessary accounts and privileges.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change all default usernames and passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/insights"&gt;CISA Cyber Insights: Enhance Email and Web Security&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Continuously scan for—and remediate—critical and high vulnerabilities.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Patch all critical and high vulnerabilities within 15 and 30 days, respectively, on internet-accessible systems. Be sure to scan for configuration vulnerabilities in addition to software vulnerabilities.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Enable automatic updates whenever possible.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Replace unsupported operating systems, applications, and hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/ed/19-01/"&gt;CISA Emergency Directive 19-01&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/insights"&gt;CISA Cyber Insights: Remediate Vulnerabilities for Internet-Accessible Systems&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Secure data in transit.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Disable Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP); enforce Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) and HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS).
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Website visitors expect their privacy to be protected. To ensure communications between the website and user are encrypted, always enforce the use of HTTPS, and enforce the use of HSTS where possible. For further information and guidance, see the U.S. Chief Information Officer (CIO) and the Federal CIO Council’s webpage on the &lt;a href="https://https.cio.gov/faq/"&gt;HTTPS-Only Standard&lt;/a&gt;. Preload HSTS for all domains, when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Disable weak cyphers (SSLv2, SSlv3, 3DES, RC4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review &lt;a href="https://cyber.dhs.gov/bod/18-01/"&gt;CISA Binding Operational Directive 18-01&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/insights"&gt;CISA Cyber Insights: Enhance Email and Web Security&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Backup data.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Employ a backup solution that automatically and continuously backs up critical data and system configurations from your website.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Keep your backup media in a safe and physically remote environment.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Test disaster recovery scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Secure web applications.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Identify and remediate the top 10 most critical web application security risks; then move on to other less critical vulnerabilities. (Refer to &lt;a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Category:OWASP_Top_Ten_Project"&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt; for a list of the most critical web application security risks.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enable logging and regularly audit website logs to detect security events or improper access.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Send the logs to a centralized log server.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Implement MFA for user logins to web applications and the underlying website infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Secure web servers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use security checklists.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Audit and harden configurations based on security checklists specific to each application (e.g., Apache, MySQL) on the system.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use application allow listing and disable modules or features that provide capabilities that are not necessary for business needs.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Implement network segmentation and segregation.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Network segmentation and segregation makes it more difficult for attackers to move laterally within connected networks. For example, placing the web server in a properly configured demilitarized zone (DMZ) limits the type of network traffic permitted between systems in the DMZ and systems in the internal corporate network.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Know where your assets are.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;You must know where your assets are in order to protect them. For example, if you have data that does not need to be on the web server, remove it to protect it from public access.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;What are some additional steps to protect against website attacks?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanitize all user input. &lt;/strong&gt;Sanitize user input, such as special characters and null characters, at both the client end and the server end. Sanitizing user input is especially critical when it is incorporated into scripts or structured query language statements.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase resource availability. &lt;/strong&gt;Configure website caching to optimize resource availability. Optimizing a website’s resource availability increases the chance that it will withstand unexpectedly high amounts of traffic during DoS attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement cross-site scripting (XSS) and cross-site request forgery (XSRF) protections.&lt;/strong&gt; Protect website systems, as well as website visitors, by implementing XSS and XSRF protections.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement a Content Security Policy (CSP).&lt;/strong&gt; Website owners should also consider implementing a CSP. Implementing a CSP lessens the chances of an attacker successfully loading and running malicious JavaScript on the end user machine.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audit third-party code. &lt;/strong&gt;Audit third-party services (e.g., ads, analytics) to validate that no unexpected code is being delivered to the end user. Website owners should weigh the pros and cons of vetting the third-party code and hosting it on the web server (as opposed to loading the code from the third party).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement additional security measures. &lt;/strong&gt;Additional measures include:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Running static and dynamic security scans against the website code and system,&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Deploying web application firewalls,&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Leveraging content delivery networks to protect against malicious web traffic, and&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Providing load balancing and resilience against high amounts of traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Additional Information&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional guidance, see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cisa.gov/cyber-essentials"&gt;CISA Cyber Essentials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-44/version-2/final"&gt;Special Publication (SP) 800-44: Guidelines on Securing Public Web Servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;NIST &lt;a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/publications/detail/sp/800-95/final"&gt;SP 800-95: Guide to Secure Web Services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.us-cert.gov/mailing-lists-and-feeds"&gt;Subscribe to Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) Current Activities&lt;/a&gt; to stay current on the latest website technology vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
Author: CISA
            &lt;div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p class="privacy-and-terms"&gt;This product is provided subject to this &lt;a href="https://us-cert.cisa.gov/privacy/notification"&gt;Notification&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/privacy-policy"&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Use&lt;/a&gt; policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 16:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>CISA</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">10542 at https://us-cert.cisa.gov</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
